What could this man
possibly need from me?
I'm exhausted today
and I want to go home now.
So, what did you want me to join you for?
For a mock battle.
A-a mock battle?
I don't think I've had a training partner
since I went to those schools.
I may not seem like it,
but I'm quite famous in the royal capital.
Choose whatever you'd like.
Let me see what
you're truly capable of, Mr. Hero.
This is a godsend for a budding adventurer!
Right, let's start our battle.
I don't know how much of a challenge
I'll be for him,
but I'll take this as a chance to train
with someone more skillful than me.
A mock battle with Captain Gilbert?
Who even is that guy?
Hope he enjoys the afterlife.
All right, let's do this.
Such polished movement,
and the way he controls
his pace is impressive.
He had to have trained like crazy
to get himself to this level.
But...
why's he so slow?
Oh, I think I get it.
With me as his opponent,
he sees no point in showing
even a glimpse of what he can really do.
Time out.
What?
I know you're taking it easy on me,
but you don't have
to hold back that much.
Noted.
Was I taking it down a notch
because he's a normal human?
Sorry about that.
He's much faster than before.
But, more importantly...
the moment I evade him,
he leaves himself completely open.
It's like he's luring me in...
Why?
Why won't my spear touch him?
No, this is a trap.
I don't think he's seriously fighting.
Damn... Try this on for size!
He changed it up there!
Gotcha!
Not even close!
I can still handle more.
You can speed up.
Oh yeah?
Could it be that...
he's already giving it all he's got?
After all that solitary training I did...
I might actually be getting stronger.
Then even I... could maybe wi-
Dragrave!
Okay. This one's my loss.
That was close.
Unbelievable.
How could anyone
evade the captain's Dragrave?
He was using a practice spear
with a wide tip
so the wind force sent that guy flying.
If it was a battle spear,
he would have lost his head.
Yeah, really.
People with talent like Captain Gilbert
are one in a million.
Talent, huh?
I noticed I had a gift for this
the moment I held a spear.
Enough!
Gilbert is the winner!
That's the guy they talk about
in the royal capital...
The difference in their power
is clear as day.
There's no one in this village
that can beat that guy anymore.
The more I trained,
the more polished my technique,
and the more strength I'd gain.
But...
Did you enjoy yourself in our village?
Yeah, right. That was painfully boring.
I hear you go around to various areas
searching for the strong,
but I don't think there's anyone
around here that can match you.
Well, I've beaten every worthy opponent
in the royal capital.
I left there with high hopes, but...
According to the rumors,
the balance of power between the kingdom
and their foreign neighbors is falling apart.
Right now, those countries
are calling for strong troops,
and those troops will gather
in search of fortune and fame.
Perhaps you should go home
and see about that.
Return to the capital
that is assembling its power.
I returned to the royal capital and
single-mindedly continued hunting demons.
When I heard someone formidable
had joined the corps,
I challenged them to fights,
and I thoroughly trounced them.
This isn't enough.
Is there no one who can give me
a real challenge?
I'm tired of this.
Every fiber of my being is bored.
I am surrounded by weaklings!
So this is where you are.
Instructor.
You're looking glum for someone who's had
the honorable alias of "Spear Sovereign"
bestowed upon them.
Just another bothersome title
thrust upon me.
How rude.
I didn't realize a title equal to my
Sword Sovereign rank was such a burden.
It's boring.
I'm sick of all these chumps.
What about Ines?
Ines?
It's like, she's strong
in a different way.
But in a simple mock battle,
I'd come out on top.
Is that so?
It'd be so much more interesting
if there were more competent people
like you, Instructor.
Like me, huh?
That does sound amusing.
You must be bored too, right?
Training soldiers and adventurers
who hardly equal the power
of one of your pinkies.
In any case, I am to protect
the royal capital.
I can't win a war by myself,
no matter how strong I am.
Besides,
someday, there will appear someone
who will surpass me.
Someday, huh.
I hope they show up
while I'm still in this position.
I might keel over from boredom first.
A man who defeated a minotaur
all on his own...
I wanted to know what kind of person
could do that, but he makes no sense.
He showed not one ounce of interest
in the most lavish of rewards,
and he was so discourteous,
even in audience with the king.
I thought he was all right.
However...
it didn't feel like he had the power
to kill that monster at all.
But even so...
Why?
Why won't my spear touch him?
I can still handle more.
You can speed up.
Oh yeah?
In that case...
I'm coming at you full-force, as you wish.
Much faster than the speed of sound,
and my most powerful technique-
I knew that if I let something like that
loose on a person they'd die.
It was the only way I could make him
feel my spear in that moment!
Dragrave!
I had no idea what happened.
For the first time in a head-on battle,
I was thoroughly defeated.
Furthermore...
I give up. I've lost.
What'd you say?
I get it.
There's no point in continuing to fight.
Was he showing concern for me because
we were in front of my subordinates?
I'd never been so humiliated.
What? What is it that you "get"?
Yeah, let's stop.
We've fought plenty.
Moreover, those words he said as he left...
I look forward to
meeting up with you again.
What are those cracks?
When did that happen?
I have no idea how he did that...
Regardless, he evaded my technique,
and he did it while I was at full strength.
Looks like things are
finally going to get exciting.
But jeez, that was an amazing attack!
There I was,
thinking I was becoming stronger...
but even after using Physical Enhancement
and Featherstep to avoid it...
If he hadn't held back just enough
so that I could get away,
I'd be dead by now.
He went out of his way to warn me
that pride will lead to death.
That Al-something...
No, Gil...?
Pretty sure it was something-"bird."
Bird...
Filbird?
That can't be right.
I'm grateful he did all that.
I'm still weak.
I have to toughen up even more.
Oh, wow!
This is shockingly good
at getting that mud out!
It even gets the stubborn stuff
stuck at the bottom!
This sword really is great!
Hey, he sure made quick work of that.
Didn't he? He does such a wonderful job.
Just like Lynne's dad said,
even if you're a little rough with it,
it won't get a scratch.
Well, it was pretty shabby when I got it,
so maybe I'm just not paying attention.
Noor!
Can you take care of mine next?
Yeah, leave it to me!
I'm glad my ditch clearing job
is going well, but...
Thanks to that I've had to stop
my soil hauling job for a while.
Since I can only take F-rank jobs,
if work in the royal capital dries up,
there'll be entire days
where I have nothing to do.
Now that I've got this,
I may as well use it to try to be useful
to people or something.
I could use this as an oar...
Nah, I'd have to buy a boat first.
And it costs money to rent an oven.
Oh, yeah!
As long as I have the space to do it,
I can use it as a griddle.
But... the problem is the fire power.
Tiny Flame.
With my abilities, the best I can do
is light my fingertip about this much.
Even though I trained
so much at those schools,
I could only acquire skills
of the lowest level.
Lord Noor, good morning.
Lynne...
You are not permitted to take on
such a familiar manner as you did.
..burg, my lady.
Just call me Lynne.
Did someone say something
to you about that?
Uh, no. Anyways, what are you doing here?
Sorry for just showing up like this.
I asked the guildmaster where you were...
Am I bothering you?
No.
I didn't tell him the exact location though...
Now that I think about it,
she can find out where
other people are using her skills.
Why are you here to see me again?
Well, I have a special request
to ask of you today.
I want you to accept me as your page.
What even is that?
Well.
A page is someone who takes care
of your everyday necessities,
as they learn techniques
and absorb knowledge from you.
If I had to say, it's somewhat close
to an assistant, or having an apprentice.
Just allowing me
to be around you is enough.
I will cause you no trouble,
so if you could please let me-
No, thanks.
Huh?
Th-then, there was something
you were unhappy with from the other day?
Or perhaps, you think someone
as young as I would be unreliable?
No.
If you let me stay,
I'm sure I can be of use to you.
I may not look it,
but I've achieved the highest marks ever
in all six training schools!
That isn't the problem.
There's nothing at all that I can teach you.
I don't think you can help me,
because I can do what I need to on my own.
Th-then my family will
pay you a handsome instructor's fee.
No, I don't need that.
In that case, you can use me
to do whatever you'd like.
As an assistant for requests from
the adventurer's guild, or for odd jobs,
anything at all!
I don't need you to do that either.
Th-then...
I just don't have a need for you.
I'm serious.
I'll do whatever it takes to show you
I can be of help to you...
I hope this will make you believe me.
Now, pardon me.
Icicle Dance!
Hellflare!
This is one of the highest levels
of magic skills that I can use.
It's called Hellflare.
And...
Mist Blade.
This is a secret of the thief class.
The Sovereign of Shadows,
Instructor Carew,
was kind enough to impart
this knowledge unto me.
And also...
Divine Slash!
What I just showed you is the sacred-class
skill of a swordsman, Divine Slash.
It's a highly specialized technique,
especially effective against the undead,
and also-
I get it. That's enough.
Th-then do I have permission
to become the page of-
Still no.
Why is she doing all this?
It seems she's mistaken me for
a person who's worth learning from.
After seeing everything she just did,
I understand her talents well.
I almost feel pitiful compared to her.
It's become more and more obvious
there's nothing I can teach you.
I-I'm...
But my power has been recognized
by the Six Sovereigns,
and if you let me join you,
I'm sure I can assist you in some way!
I still think I'm nothing compared to you,
but I beg of you!
How can I make her understand?
Maybe it's best
to just show her the reality...
Earlier, you showed me
a lot of amazing skills you have,
but I'll show you my own skills now.
Tiny Flame.
The young boy with no talent.
The instructors at the royal capital's
training schools would tell stories
of this young boy.
However, everyone interpreted them
as fairy tales, created to teach lessons.
Because the idea of that
young boy was preposterous.
As a twelve-year-old,
he attended all six training courses
known for their rigorous nature
at the royal schools,
and completed the full term for each.
That sort of person cannot possibly exist.
Everyone knows that.
The brawniest warrior would give up
after three days in that three-month
long course, let alone a child...
I thought the same thing...
until I met that person.
Instructor Oken
showed me something once.
What interesting thing
do you have to show me?
Lady Lynneburg, have a look.
The Tiny Flame got bigger!
Aha!
Interesting, yes?
Depending on the training,
even the base level skill
Tiny Flame can grow this large.
It has absolutely no practical use,
and for me who has lived
more than 200 years and has some time
on his hands, it's just a bit of fun.
Tiny Flame.
I tried countless times
to do it myself too,
but I couldn't make the flame
even slightly larger.
This is not something
that could be done in a day,
but it requires devotion to your studies
for a very long time.
And that's precisely why
I was stunned speechless.
It was many times bigger than what the
world's greatest sorcerer Oken had done.
A Tiny Flame
that far outclassed the others.
This is my Tiny Flame.
The other five class skills
are just like this one.
Do you understand what this means?
Basically, all six of his class skills
are extraordinary.
What did I just show to that
monumentally powerful person?
Just showing off some high-level skills
that I've only memorized?
He repelled those attacks from that Minotaur's axe
with only a single broadsword
in his hands numerous times.
He didn't brag about his power and
quietly went on working for other people.
If I could put it into one word,
I'd say he's strong.
Not only in body, but in mind as well.
He has the fortitude
to live life on his own,
so he will never yield to anyone.
In the future, I will be in the position
to lead this kingdom alongside my brother.
The motto of the Clays royal family is
"Those of royal blood must be strong."
That's why more than anything I must learn
how to achieve strength like that.
Thanks for the meal!
Lord Noor. I've figured it out.
My own pride, as well as my immaturity.
Until the day comes when
you will recognize me as your page...
Until that happens, I will follow
behind you wherever you may go.
Lord Noor. No...
Instructor Noor.
"Instructor"?
Because the answer
that I am in pursuit of...
no, the supreme "strength"
that generations upon generations
of the Clays royal family have sought
resides within this man.
How... did this happen?
#3 I Parry Taking on a Page